<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-01-09T16:24:32-07:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Human Behavior Project</title><subtitle>The Human Behavior Project (HBP) aims to integrate the behavioral sciences through natural language processing algorithms.  The project is predicated on what we term the Reverse Progress Problem of the Behavioral Sciences, and accomplished through  the production of the Internomological Network Search Engine.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Behavior change interventions: The potential of ontologies for advancing science and practice</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2016/12/07/behavior-change-interventions-potential-ontologies-advancing-science-and-practice.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Behavior change interventions: The potential of ontologies for advancing science and practice" /><published>2016-12-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-12-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2016/12/07/behavior-change-interventions-potential-ontologies-advancing-science-and-practice</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2016/12/07/behavior-change-interventions-potential-ontologies-advancing-science-and-practice.html">&lt;p&gt;Kai R. Larsen recently published a paper in &quot;Journal of Behavioral Medicine&quot; co-authored by Susan Michie, Eric Hekler, and Jean Yi. A central goal of behavioral medicine is the creation of evidence-based interventions for promoting behavior change. Scientific knowledge about behavior change could be more effectively accumulated using &quot;ontologies.&quot; In information science, an ontology is a systematic method for articulating a &quot;controlled vocabulary&quot; of agreed-upon terms and their inter-relationships. It involves three core elements: (1) a controlled vocabulary specifying and defining existing classes; (2) specification of the inter-relationships between classes; and (3) codification in a computer-readable format to enable knowledge generation, organization, reuse, integration, and analysis. This paper introduces ontologies, provides a review of current efforts to create ontologies related to behavior change interventions and suggests future work. August (2016)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Research" /><category term="Article" /><summary type="html">Kai R. Larsen recently published a paper in &quot;Journal of Behavioral Medicine&quot; co-authored by Susan Michie, Eric Hekler, and Jean Yi. A central goal of behavioral medicine is the creation of evidence-based interventions for promoting behavior change. Scientific knowledge about behavior change could be more effectively accumulated using &quot;ontologies.&quot; In information science, an ontology is a systematic method for articulating a &quot;controlled vocabulary&quot; of agreed-upon terms and their inter-relationships. It involves three core elements: (1) a controlled vocabulary specifying and defining existing classes; (2) specification of the inter-relationships between classes; and (3) codification in a computer-readable format to enable knowledge generation, organization, reuse, integration, and analysis. This paper introduces ontologies, provides a review of current efforts to create ontologies related to behavior change interventions and suggests future work. August (2016)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">NSF Workshop on Behavioral Ontology Learning</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2016/12/07/nsf-workshop-behavioral-ontology-learning.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="NSF Workshop on Behavioral Ontology Learning" /><published>2016-12-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-12-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2016/12/07/nsf-workshop-behavioral-ontology-learning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2016/12/07/nsf-workshop-behavioral-ontology-learning.html">&lt;p&gt;We are proud to be hosting a NSF Workshop on Behavioral Ontology Learning in Estes park this coming August. We are very excited to have key note speaker Bill Riley, Director of NIH Office of Behavioral and Social Science Research, speak with us at the workshop. For more information please visit:  http://cmci.colorado.edu/~mpaul/wbol/&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="NSF" /><category term="Workshop" /><summary type="html">We are proud to be hosting a NSF Workshop on Behavioral Ontology Learning in Estes park this coming August. We are very excited to have key note speaker Bill Riley, Director of NIH Office of Behavioral and Social Science Research, speak with us at the workshop. For more information please visit: http://cmci.colorado.edu/~mpaul/wbol/</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">A Tool for Addressing Construct Identity in Literature Reviews and Meta-Analyses, MIS Quarterly publication Sept. 2016</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2016/12/07/tool-addressing-construct-identity-literature-reviews-and-meta-analyses-mis-quarterly.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A Tool for Addressing Construct Identity in Literature Reviews and Meta-Analyses, MIS Quarterly publication Sept. 2016" /><published>2016-12-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2016-12-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2016/12/07/tool-addressing-construct-identity-literature-reviews-and-meta-analyses-mis-quarterly</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2016/12/07/tool-addressing-construct-identity-literature-reviews-and-meta-analyses-mis-quarterly.html">&lt;p&gt;Kai R. Larsen and Chih How Bong were recently featured in &lt;a href=&quot;https://misq.org/a-tool-for-addressing-construct-identity-in-literature-reviews-and-meta-analyses.html&quot;&gt;an article they published in MIS Quarterly on construct identity&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;The problem of detecting whether two behavioral constructs reference the same real world phenomenon has existed for over 100 years; we term discordant naming of constructs the Construct Identity Fallacy (CIF). We designed and evaluated the Construct Identity Detector (CID), the first tool with large-scale construct identity detection properties and the first tool that does not require respondent data. Through the adaptation and combination of different natural language processing (NLP) algorithms, six designs were created and evaluated against human expert decisions. All six designs were found capable of detecting construct identity, and a design combining two existing algorithms significantly outperformed the other approaches. A set of follow-up studies suggests the tool is valuable as a supplement to expert efforts in literature review and meta-analysis. Beyond Design Science contributions, this article has important implications related to the taxonomic structure of social- and behavioral-science constructs, for the jingle and jangle fallacy, the core of the Information Systems (IS) nomological network, and the inaccessibility of social and behavioral science knowledge. In sum, CID represents an important, albeit tentative, step towards discipline-wide identification of construct identities.&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Research" /><category term="Article" /><summary type="html">Kai R. Larsen and Chih How Bong were recently featured in an article they published in MIS Quarterly on construct identity. Abstract: The problem of detecting whether two behavioral constructs reference the same real world phenomenon has existed for over 100 years; we term discordant naming of constructs the Construct Identity Fallacy (CIF). We designed and evaluated the Construct Identity Detector (CID), the first tool with large-scale construct identity detection properties and the first tool that does not require respondent data. Through the adaptation and combination of different natural language processing (NLP) algorithms, six designs were created and evaluated against human expert decisions. All six designs were found capable of detecting construct identity, and a design combining two existing algorithms significantly outperformed the other approaches. A set of follow-up studies suggests the tool is valuable as a supplement to expert efforts in literature review and meta-analysis. Beyond Design Science contributions, this article has important implications related to the taxonomic structure of social- and behavioral-science constructs, for the jingle and jangle fallacy, the core of the Information Systems (IS) nomological network, and the inaccessibility of social and behavioral science knowledge. In sum, CID represents an important, albeit tentative, step towards discipline-wide identification of construct identities.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hovorka and Co-Author’s paper nominated for best paper at HICSS</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2013/01/29/hovorka-and-co-authors-paper-nominated-best-paper-hicss.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hovorka and Co-Author's paper nominated for best paper at HICSS" /><published>2013-01-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-01-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2013/01/29/hovorka-and-co-authors-paper-nominated-best-paper-hicss</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2013/01/29/hovorka-and-co-authors-paper-nominated-best-paper-hicss.html">&lt;p&gt;Dirk S. Hovorka, Kai R. Larsen, James Birt, and Gavin Finnie's paper &quot;A Meta-theoretic Approach to Theory Integration in Information Systems&quot; has been nominated for &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hicss.hawaii.edu/hicss_46/bp46/bestpapersnoms1219.pdf&quot;&gt;Best Paper&lt;/a&gt; in the category of Organizational Systems and Technology at the Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hicss.hawaii.edu&quot;&gt;HICSS&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dirk S. Hovorka, Kai R. Larsen, James Birt, and Gavin Finnie's paper &quot;A Meta-theoretic Approach to Theory Integration in Information Systems&quot; has been nominated for Best Paper in the category of Organizational Systems and Technology at the Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences (HICSS).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Human Behavior Project research team assists in NIH report on GEM website</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2013/01/29/human-behavior-project-research-team-assists-nih-report-gem-website.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Human Behavior Project research team assists in NIH report on GEM website" /><published>2013-01-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2013-01-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2013/01/29/human-behavior-project-research-team-assists-nih-report-gem-website</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2013/01/29/human-behavior-project-research-team-assists-nih-report-gem-website.html">&lt;p&gt;Team members at the Human Behavior Project completed a report for NIH that evaluated the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gem-beta.org/Public/Home.aspx&quot;&gt;GEM&lt;/a&gt; (Grid-Enabled Measures Database) website for possible improvements. GEM is a tool for researchers to share and discover related research information. Evaluation focused on suggestions that would encourage users to share information about constructs and measures that will increase the ability to detect construct synonymy and similarity. More information about the goals of GEM can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://cancercontrol.cancer.gov/BRP/gem.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Team members at the Human Behavior Project completed a report for NIH that evaluated the GEM (Grid-Enabled Measures Database) website for possible improvements. GEM is a tool for researchers to share and discover related research information. Evaluation focused on suggestions that would encourage users to share information about constructs and measures that will increase the ability to detect construct synonymy and similarity. More information about the goals of GEM can be found here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Symposium by Cook, Sousa, Meek and Larsen accepted for podium presentation at WIN’s 46th Annual Communicating Nursing Research Conference</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/12/27/symposium-cook-sousa-meek-and-larsen-accepted-podium-presentation-wins-46th-annual.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Symposium by Cook, Sousa, Meek and Larsen accepted for podium presentation at WIN's 46th Annual Communicating Nursing Research Conference" /><published>2012-12-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2012-12-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/12/27/symposium-cook-sousa-meek-and-larsen-accepted-podium-presentation-wins-46th-annual</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/12/27/symposium-cook-sousa-meek-and-larsen-accepted-podium-presentation-wins-46th-annual.html">&lt;p&gt;Paul Cook's, Karen Sousa's, Paula Meek's and Kai Larsen's symposium, &quot;Finding Meaning in the Magic Kingdom of Methods: Neverland or Tomorrowland?&quot;, will be presented on April 11, 2013, by Paul Cook at the Western Institute of Nursing's 46th Annual Communicating Nursing Research Conference at the Disneyland Hotel in Anaheim, CA. More information about the conference can be found &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.winursing.org/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Paul Cook's, Karen Sousa's, Paula Meek's and Kai Larsen's symposium, &quot;Finding Meaning in the Magic Kingdom of Methods: Neverland or Tomorrowland?&quot;, will be presented on April 11, 2013, by Paul Cook at the Western Institute of Nursing's 46th Annual Communicating Nursing Research Conference at the Disneyland Hotel in Anaheim, CA. More information about the conference can be found here.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hovorka and Co-Authors’ paper accepted at Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/09/03/hovorka-and-co-authors-paper-accepted-hawaii-international-conference-system-sciences.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hovorka and Co-Authors' paper accepted at Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences" /><published>2012-09-03T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2012-09-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/09/03/hovorka-and-co-authors-paper-accepted-hawaii-international-conference-system-sciences</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/09/03/hovorka-and-co-authors-paper-accepted-hawaii-international-conference-system-sciences.html">&lt;p&gt;Dirk S. Hovorka, Kai R. Larsen, James Birt, and Gavin Finnie's paper &quot;A Meta-theoretic Approach to Theory Integration in Information Systems&quot; was accepted at the 46th annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hicss.hawaii.edu/&quot;&gt;HICSS&lt;/a&gt;) for January 2013.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Dirk S. Hovorka, Kai R. Larsen, James Birt, and Gavin Finnie's paper &quot;A Meta-theoretic Approach to Theory Integration in Information Systems&quot; was accepted at the 46th annual Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences (HICSS) for January 2013.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Chih How Bong presents at IEEE Symposium on Computer and Informatics</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/05/29/chih-how-bong-presents-ieee-symposium-computer-and-informatics.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Chih How Bong presents at IEEE Symposium on Computer and Informatics" /><published>2012-05-29T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2012-05-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/05/29/chih-how-bong-presents-ieee-symposium-computer-and-informatics</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/05/29/chih-how-bong-presents-ieee-symposium-computer-and-informatics.html">&lt;p&gt;Bong, C. H., K. R. Larsen, J. Martin (2012). Large Scale Integration of Antecedents to Decision Making. IEEE Symposium on Computer and Informatics. Penang, Malaysia, IEEE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chih How Bong was a PhD student under Professor Kai Larsen's advising at CU-Boulder. Bong received his PhD in Computer Science in 2011.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Bong, C. H., K. R. Larsen, J. Martin (2012). Large Scale Integration of Antecedents to Decision Making. IEEE Symposium on Computer and Informatics. Penang, Malaysia, IEEE. Chih How Bong was a PhD student under Professor Kai Larsen's advising at CU-Boulder. Bong received his PhD in Computer Science in 2011.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jingjing Li and Kai Larsen present at International Conference on Information Systems</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/05/29/jingjing-li-and-kai-larsen-present-international-conference-information-systems.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jingjing Li and Kai Larsen present at International Conference on Information Systems" /><published>2012-05-29T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2012-05-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/05/29/jingjing-li-and-kai-larsen-present-international-conference-information-systems</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/05/29/jingjing-li-and-kai-larsen-present-international-conference-information-systems.html">&lt;p&gt;Jingjing Li and Kai R. Larsen, &quot;Establishing Nomological Networks for Behavioral Science: a Natural Language Processing Based Approach,&quot; International Conference on Information Systems (ICIS), Shanghai, China, December 4th-7th, 2011.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jingjing Li is a PhD candidate at the Leeds School of Business at CU-Boulder, and is a member of the Human Behavior Project development team.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Jingjing Li and Kai R. Larsen, &quot;Establishing Nomological Networks for Behavioral Science: a Natural Language Processing Based Approach,&quot; International Conference on Information Systems (ICIS), Shanghai, China, December 4th-7th, 2011. Jingjing Li is a PhD candidate at the Leeds School of Business at CU-Boulder, and is a member of the Human Behavior Project development team.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Kai Larsen and Co-Author Dirk Hovorka present at Hawaii International Conference on System Science</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/05/29/kai-larsen-and-co-author-dirk-hovorka-present-hawaii-international-conference-system-science.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Kai Larsen and Co-Author Dirk Hovorka present at Hawaii International Conference on System Science" /><published>2012-05-29T00:00:00-06:00</published><updated>2012-05-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/05/29/kai-larsen-and-co-author-dirk-hovorka-present-hawaii-international-conference-system-science</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/2012/05/29/kai-larsen-and-co-author-dirk-hovorka-present-hawaii-international-conference-system-science.html">&lt;p&gt;Kai R. Larsen and Dirk S. Hovorka, &quot;Developing Interfield Nomological Nets,&quot; Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences (HICSS), Maui, Hawaii, January 4th-7th, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Kai R. Larsen and Dirk S. Hovorka, &quot;Developing Interfield Nomological Nets,&quot; Hawaii International Conference on System Sciences (HICSS), Maui, Hawaii, January 4th-7th, 2012.</summary></entry></feed>